Adiela Abishua

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+254723644152 | adiela.abishua@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/adielaabishua | https://github.com/adiela

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a software engineer with over 5 years of professional experience. I have built consumer and B2B software. I am passionate about the use of technology in creating real world solutions. Some technologies I enjoy working with include JavaScript(ReactJS, React Native, VueJS, NodeJS), Python (Django, Flask) and SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Career Break - Full-time Parenting

APRIL 2023 - MARCH 2024

Full-Stack Software Engineer — Slim.Ai

JUNE 2021 - MARCH 2023

- Development of developer tool SaaS platform that allowed users to scan, and resize containers
- Integrated user analytics tools to the Saas platform
- Developed SaaS native data store interface and backend
- Developed SaaS management dashboard

Contract Software Engineer - Xetova

JUNE 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

- Development of supply chain management software
- Developed supply chain management reporting software written in Python and JavaScript. Wrote 90% of code with minimal supervision.
- Led development of inhouse crm software.

Full-Stack Software Engineer — Angaza

FEBRUARY 2019 - APRIL 2020

- Development of SaaS platform that manages millions of pay-as-you-go and direct sales of solar products in 40+ countries.
- Collaborated with a distributed team of software engineers in an agile development process. Provided technical support for usage of the SaaS platform.
- Collaborated in building customer attributes feature
- Built a customer attributes filtering feature
- Collaborated in rebuilding the user transactions interface

Frontend Web Developer — Twende Carpool

OCTOBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- Translated user experience design (mockups, wireframes and user journeys) into code.
- Development of customer facing website
- Development of web platform for ride sharing application

SKILLS

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang
- Databases/ Datastores: MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Redis
- Frameworks/ Libraries: Django, Flask, React, React Native, Redux, Angular, VueJs, ExpressJs, NodeJs
- Tools: Git, Docker, Celery, RabbitMQ, AWS Cloud, Google Cloud Platfrorm, CI/CD

EDUCATION

Full-Stack web development bootcamp Moringa School

MAY 2018 - AUGUST 2018

BSc. International Business Administration - Finance United States International University - Africa 2013-2018